Kyle Wang

Software Engineer | Node | React | Vue | PHP

Software engineer possesses expertise in JavaScript and PHP frameworks, demonstrating a profound understanding of OOP principles, Data Structures, and Design Patterns. Experienced in responsive mobile/web development, collaborating effectively with client-side and distributed development teams. Well-versed in working with web systems across various OS and browsers. Having a strong understanding of agile methodologies, CI/CD pipelines, and microservices.

Work experience

Senior Full-Stack Developer | Typescript | React | Express.js | Prisma | GraphQL | Postgresql | AWS Pollfish, Inc. NY, USA / From January 2023 to March 2024 Pollfish, Inc. is a software-as-a-service company which provides user-friendly survey platform that provides real-time market research data to businesses and organizations.

- Led the development of survey management workflow enabling clients to create, share surveys, and analyze customer feedback.
- Designed a PostgreSQL-based database and developed backend with Express.js, GraphQL, Prisma.
- Engaged in frontend development utilizing Next.js and TypeScript, incorporating cutting-edge libraries such as Turbo, Zustand, Tanstack, and Zod.
- Implemented responsive design across various devices.
- Implemented audience target delivering workflow.
- Integrated Stripe Payments for payment transactions.
- Introduced Graphite, a code review tool, to facilitate the creation of smaller sized pull requests(PRs), making the code review process more efficient and collaborative.

Technologies: Typescript, React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Stripe, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Prisma, GraphQL, AWS, Graphite https://pollfish.com

Full-Stack Developer | TypeScript | Nuxt.js | Laravel | JS Chart | GraphQL Earl Owen Company, Inc. TX, USA / From March 2021 to October 2022

Earl Owen Company, Inc. is a warehouse distributor which carries a wide variety of aftermarket automotive accessories.

- Improved customer frontend based on provided Figma designs using Vue.js.
- Developed an admin application utilizing Vue.js, Laravel.
- Created various multi-chart like Line Chart, Bar Chart, Pie Chart and Bubble Chart integrated with backend APIs.
- Ensured full responsiveness of the application and smooth animations on mobile devices.
- Refactored the code on the frontend by eliminating redundancy and enhancing code scalability.
- Collaborated with backend team to define GraphQL queries and mutations for efficient API requests, improving data retrieval and submission processes.

Technologies: TypeScript, Vue, Nuxt.js, Vuex, Vuetify, CanvasJS Chart, Jest, Laravel, GraphQL, AWS, Git https://www.earlowen.com

✓ alijourney589@gmail.com

skills

HTML5 / CSS / SASS

Bootstrap / TailwindCSS / MaterialUI

Javascript / Typescript

React / Next.js / Gatsby.js

Vue / Nuxt.js

Node.js / Express.js / Nest.js

Php / Laravel

Jest / Cypress

Sequelize / Prisma

GraphQL / REST API

PostgreSQL / MySQL / MongoDB

Solidity

Git / Docker

AWS

Google Cloud Services

Work experience

Front-end Developer | React | Storybook | Jest ZooKeep Tokyo, JP / From September 2020 to February 2021

ZooKeep is a Software-as-a-service company which provides platform for a tech driven, hands-on HR & Recruitment Consulting Service.

- Cross-functionally collaborated with design and backend development teams to implement seamless user interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Contributed in the development of modern web applications using React.js contributing to a 15% increase in site traffic.
- Played an active role in code reviews, consistently ensuring adherence to coding standards and best practices. This commitment resulted in 10% reduction in postrelease issues.
- Collaborated closely with the UX/UI team, successfully translating wireframes and mockups into functional, user-friendly interfaces.

Technologies: JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Storybook, Webpack, Jest https://www.zookeep.com

Full-Stack developer | Vue | GraphQL | Jest | Storybook Klassboard Paris ile de France / From November 2018 to June 2020

Klassroom provides school management platform that aims to streamline communication and enhance collaboration within the school community.

- Developed various features such as Classroom management, School Leadership Dashboard and Parent-Teacher communication features.
- Developed pixel-perfect and mobile-responsive front-end pages using Vue.js and Vuetify.
- Created reusable shared components like datepicker, dropdown, table, and more according to the provided Figma designs.
- Built a lightweight but robust video-calling web application with Twilio.
- Enhanced website performance, resulting in a 30% decrease in page load times.
- Collaborated with the backend team to integrate GraphQL improving overall functionality.

Technologies: Vue, Vuetify, Vuex, Custom components, Storybook, Twilio, GraphQL, Jest

https://www.klassboard.com

Freelancer Freelancer USA / From January 2016 to April 2018 Served as a freelancer, managing various projects.

Education

Bachelor's degree Valparaiso University IN / From September 2014 to August 2018